let's talk about music how often do you
listen to music I think I listen to
music mostly when I'm driving I think it
puts me in such a good mood when I'm
like out there on a drive and I play my
favorite music I'm usually into afro
music a lot hip-hop and afro and R&B so
I prefer listening to music when I'm
driving or sometimes when I'm working
out I'm at the gym something like that
is music an important subject in schools
in your country in schools in my country
it is because you know um I'm from India
so in India music and dance and um
expressing our emotions is usually
through music and uh dancing so in every
school they teach classical music or
they have a subject where there is
something about music usually so I think
it is important do you ever go to live
concerts oh I've been to three concerts
and three of them are my favorite
artists and it was actually on my um
wish list and I made it happen and uh it
was one of the best
experiences and uh in live concerts it's
a lot different than you would imagine
um just have to keep your energy uh
straight and it's it's like um it's like
you can't believe it's happening now
let's talk about magazines and
newspapers do you prefer to read
magazines or newspapers definitely
magazines um mostly on the topics of
fashion or Interior Design This is what
I really like because I like to see
creative sides all from all over the
world I like to see what people are
talking about what's new what's trending
and um I like to learn like I like to
have knowledge of things of like what is
this called what is that called CU
usually when you see pictures you don't
usually know what it's called so when
you read a magazine know where you get
the knowledge that's that's where you
get to know oh this fabric is called
this or this uh decor a is called that
so I think it's very good on information
do you think you can learn as much from
a magazine as a book definitely not cuz
magazine is like a shorter version of
what's in a book so I definitely prefer
books over magazines do you think that
you will continue to read paper based
magazines in the future I think I'm very
old-fashioned like that I need to have a
physical book in my hand and that's how
I think it produces serotonin in my
brain otherwise no
digital it's very different it's I I
like uh physically reading a magazine or
a book now let's talk about outdoor
activities do you like being outdoors I
love being outdoors um I usually spend
my time planning an activity or just
being out my friends even if I'm not
doing anything I must stay Outdoors I'm
not a very like home based person like I
can't stay home much I have to keep
moving all the time which outdoor sports
do you enjoy doing I like uh um going
out with my friends and playing football
or or some kind of uh activity like
swimming um going to the beach this is
this is something I really really enjoy
which outdoor activities are most
popular in your country definitely it's
like the game of uh India everybody
loves Cricket when you go out of your
house you're always going to see like
some kids playing uh or or also
batminton actually uh people enjoy that
a lot as well I'd like to describe my
favorite actor and actress um so my
favorite actor will be Benedict
Cumberbatch and um my favorite actress
is Angelina Julie and I like their
movies so much um they usually star in
action films or mystery films and that's
very similar to where I am like in my
personal life I love mysterious stuff
I'm I'm like always into like detective
uh theories or mystery books and stuff
like that so I always watch movies as
such and their acting is on point it's
always number one and I like Angelina
Julie also for her humanitarian work
that she does throughout her life she's
been very present uh with charity work
and um making sure that a lot of kids
are fed in countries which are
unfortunate and I really like that about
her and I also like how Fierce she is
and uh when she presents herself it's
it's very divine feminine so I really
really like that and I feel like she has
that sort of energy where um a woman can
feel powerful about herself just by
looking at her and kind of
um understanding where she comes from
she doesn't really come from a very
mentally stable place but now at this
point in her life she's a very like
strong woman and and she's done it all
herself and Benedict Kash I actually
watched his uh TV show which was called
Sherlock and I am a crazy Sherlock fan
and I'm I love mystery like I said and
um detective stories and everything and
him playing that really showed me what
kind of an incredible actor he is
because I felt like I'm watching
Sherlock Holmes from the books and not
an actor on screen and um he's also done
a movie that I really love it's called
Doctor Strange that's my favorite
superhero from The Avengers and he has
just done an amazing job uh in that
movie so we've been talking about a
famous actress and actor that that you
enjoy and we're going to continue to
talk about movies and and Theater what
are the most popular types of movies in
your country it would be to thank you
for watching this video I want to give
you a free course that has helped
thousands of students improve their I
speaking score what it's going to do is
take you through every single part of
the test and give you strategies for
part one part two and part three and
also allow you to practice at home for
free and get feedback to sign up for
that for free all you have to do is just
click the link in the description thanks
very much and let's get back to the
video it would be action and drama
definitely something that has to do with
emotional connection it's usually
fictional that I would say um and also
comedy yeah there's a lot of Comedy that
goes on in the films that are coming out
now and from India do you think that
going to the cinema will be as popular
in the future uh I think 50/50 yeah I'm
not sure about that but it looks like uh
people enjoy watching movies at home and
uh it's not as much uh exciting as it
used to be back then and um I think
probably yes it would be more digitally
available at home and uh probably yeah
now let's talk about the theater how
strong a tradition is it today in your
country to go to the theater um mostly I
think in out of City areas actually it's
mostly now as a as an activity that
families go to with their kids just to
show a play to their kids and to
introduce them to this form of um
culture and activity I think it's more
of that now uh theater is not as much
popularized uh back in India as much as
Cinema and film and movies are so I
think that is kind of on the backseat um
it's not so much as it used to be do you
think that theater should be run as a
business or as a public service oo I
think both I think it goes hand in hand
um so that people can be employed as
well at the same time and um it it is of
a public service at the same time I
think
um I think that people do enjoy it but
at the same time uh um it could be used
as an as an excuse and used as like um
an opportunity what I'm is what I mean
uh to employ people and uh because
there's a lot of people who would love
to do acting but they can't really make
it in the movies so maybe they could use
theater as um as their hobby so I think
yeah both can go hand in hand in some
countries governments pay theaters to
put on shows for the public do you think
this is good use of public money it
depends on if whether or not if it's
free to the public because if you're
charging for them to see that play then
it doesn't make any sense is what I
think and I think that it shouldn't be
this way in the first place I think it
should be available freely to the people
um yeah let me give you some feedback on
your performance so you're hoping to get
a b nine and I'll go through the four
markting criteria so pronunciation
fluency and coherence grammar and
vocabulary so let's start off with your
pronunciation to thank you for making it
this far in the video I want to give you
10% off our VIP course I VIP course is
the most successful I course in the
world that is a fact because we have
more band seven eight and nine success
stories than any other I course in the
entire world we do that by simplifying
the whole I process supporting you with
some of the best is teachers in the
world and being with you every step of
the way until you get the score that you
need all you have to do is just look
down in the description just click that
and you can sign up if you have any
questions about the VIP course always
feel free to get in touch with us we
answer 100% of the questions that we get
hope that you become a VIP if not enjoy
the rest of this free video
pronunciation is one of your your strong
points oh okay the examiner will be
thinking can I understand what this
person is saying how clear are they and
then um some higher level pronunciation
features like intonation for example I
can understand 100% of what you're
saying you do have a a hint of an accent
but it is extremely clear listening to
you for anyone watching who has an
Indian accent they shouldn't feel bad
about it or or anything like that you
know you shouldn't try and remove your
accent I think it's about speaking as
clearly as possible but you you
certainly do you also use intonation
extremely well so we use intonation to
convey meaning for example when you came
in here today and I said please sit down
very flat intonation going down do I
sound happy or rude or serious yeah a
bit rude a bit serious but if I said we
sit down my intonation is going up
sounds completely different but the
words are exactly the same so you use
intonation like that a lot to show that
you're excited about something that
you're happy about it that you're talk
that you're serious about something in a
very very high level way which is very
difficult to
learn and you do it very naturally you
also use connected speech um so for
example if you were talking about movies
someone learning English might say do
you want to go to the cinema but someone
at a high level like yourself do you
want to go want to go signs like one
word want to go cuz you're connecting
all the speech up you do that lot and
very naturally you also use um sentence
stress which where you emphasize certain
words that's your coffee so you're
you're emphasizing that word because
that's the most important word it's very
difficult to to teach that it takes a
long time to learn wow you're doing
you're doing very well in that area
fluency is are you able to speak without
unnatural pauses without unnatural
hesitation and there's there's two
reasons why people pause
and that that type of thing
audible pauses like that one one reason
is they're learning a language and
they're trying to think should I use
present simple or present perfect or you
know what's the correct adjective to use
you don't do that cuz your your language
is at quite a high level you do
sometimes pause and think and hesitate a
little bit for the second reason which
is trying to think of ideas so you can
tell especially in the part three you
were formulating ideas and you were let
me think about that and pausing a little
bit but that's natural and and a good
examiner knows the difference between
those two things so they're not going to
give you a low Mark for pausing or
hesitating a little bit for thinking of
the idea now coherence is different it's
did you answer the question and did you
develop your answers a little bit more
you need to be a little bit careful for
example the first question I asked you
how often do you listen to music and you
told me about when you listen to music
so that's slightly different M now the
examiner will base their score on all of
your answers it's not like oh she didn't
she slightly didn't answer that question
in one in one question give her a low
score that's not how it works and the
way that you answered that question by
saying I listen to music in the car and
I listen to it in the I think you said
when I drive when I drive you're
answering the question implicitly mhm by
implication I know how often you listen
to it you should try to answer each
question explicitly how often do you
every day I don't think that this is an
issue for you today but imagine you go
and do the test imagine you have a
Canadian visa application that's like if
I don't get this I'm going to I can't go
and meet you know my family or or you
know or
do whatever I want to do there's a lot
of pressure on you so often when people
are under pressure and under stress they
mess up just make sure that you answer
every question exactly how they want it
the same with the Q card for part two it
said describe your favorite actor or
actress and you did both mhm so
technically an examiner would be
extremely picky if they marked you down
for that
but again I'm not criticizing you but
I'm being overly cautious because on
exam day if you go and do the test you
might go off and talk about something
related to that topic but not really
answering it correctly I think you would
be fine but we just don't want to take
any risks definitely towards the end
especially the last question part three
what the examiner is thinking about is
can this person really develop their
answers can they speak at length about
topics the last question it was quite a
short answer for part three but that was
quite impressive I I'll tell you why if
you get a really really difficult
question in part three you should be
happy because the examiner thinks you're
good if the examiner thinks you're bad
they'll just throw easy softball
questions at you if the examiner thinks
that you're really good they'll throw
more and more difficult questions to
really just stretch you and test you and
that's what I was trying to do at the
end a really good band eight band n
student even if they get a question that
they don't know much about they're not
too sure about they will attempt it
answer so your attempt at an answer even
though it was quite short indicates that
you are at a very high level coherence
is the only area that I'm really really
concerned about but overall it's very
very good I'm focusing on the negative
but it's only because you're you should
because otherwise how would I know yeah
uh grammar The Examiner will be thinking
does this person have enough awareness
of grammar structures that they can talk
about anything like can they use
comparatives to compare two things can
they use superlatives to talk about
their favorite things and talk about the
best things whatever I throw at you
you're able to to handle that and
they'll also then think about how many
grammar mistakes are you making I think
I only only heard one or two small slips
I think like preposition slip or an
article slip but that is comparable to a
native English speaker if you listen to
native English speakers speak for 15 20
minutes they'll make little preposition
errors or subject verb agreement errors
that's natural so don't need to worry
about that and your vocabulary is also
excellent for example this you use very
topic specific words and idiomatic
language which is great only very high
level students actually do that so your
final Bond score would be the highest
one which is a bond n no way thank you
so much yeah that's amazing but but but
if on test day you didn't answer the
questions in part one you didn't really
answer the question in part two and you
didn't develop your answers enough in
part three that would drop you down a
little bit not hugely MH but just be
careful with that all right less than 1%
of people get about nine oh wow yeah so
there you go thank you